<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>php on jcbwlkr</title>
    <link>https://jacob-walker.com/categories/php.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in php on jcbwlkr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacob-walker.com/categories/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TimeIPS</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/timeips.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/timeips.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From October 2010 to February 2015 the majority of my development focus was
with my employer TimeIPS. We made a time and attendance system which is used by
thousands of companies around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing OOP</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/implementing-oop.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/implementing-oop.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in June 2014 I gave a presentation to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/devict.html&#34;&gt;devICT&lt;/a&gt; about how to use
Object Oriented Programming in PHP and Ruby. I chose this topic when I was
explaining inheritance to a friend and realized others would be interested. I
chose PHP and Ruby for examples because I was already familiar with OOP in PHP
and I wanted to learn more about Ruby&amp;rsquo;s object model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templating In PHP With Twig</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/twig.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/twig.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 2013 I gave a short presentation to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/devict.html&#34;&gt;devICT&lt;/a&gt; about the PHP
templating engine &lt;a href=&#34;http://twig.sensiolabs.org&#34;&gt;Twig&lt;/a&gt;. The talk covered the basics of
installing/configuring Twig, rendering templates, and writing templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>find.torrent</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/find.torrent.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/find.torrent.html</guid>
      <description>At home my desktop PC acts as a UPNP media server and is the box I use to download torrents. This machine was inconveniently located in my basement. There were many times when I would want to start a download but the only device nearby is my phone. I found that finding and downloading a torrent file then getting it to my torrent machine was a cumbersome process. Furthermore, many sites that index torrent files contain advertising that ranges from annoying to inappropriate to explicit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocommunicator API Client</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/geocommunicator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/geocommunicator.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who travels around the country servicing natural gas pipelines.
As part of his duties he has to translate latitude / longitude coordinates into
state, township, range, and section information. He was doing this by hand
dozens of time per day. I found an API from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geocommunicator.gov/&#34;&gt;Department of the Interior&amp;rsquo;s
Bureau of Land Management&lt;/a&gt; which accepts coordinates and responds with the
exact information my friend needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Organic Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/now.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/now.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Natural Organic Warehouse (NOW) is a distributor of organic products for
farming, gardening, and landscaping purposes. Their slogan is &amp;ldquo;better, cleaner,
sustainable choices.&amp;rdquo; Through my consulting company &lt;a href=&#34;http://tortugas-llc.com&#34;&gt;Tortugas Consulting,
LLC&lt;/a&gt; I helped to develop their online presence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norris Training Systems</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/norris-training.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/portfolio/norris-training.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://norristraining.com&#34;&gt;Norris Training Systems&lt;/a&gt; provides pre-licensing and continuing
education training to insurance agents. My consulting company &lt;a href=&#34;http://tortugas-llc.com&#34;&gt;Tortugas
Consulting, LLC&lt;/a&gt; developed their e-commerce website which allows
agents to purchase and schedule classes. Additionally agents can download
documents associated with their course and take related quizzes to prepare for
their state license exam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Clone and Shallow vs Deep Copying</title>
      <link>https://jacob-walker.com/blog/php-clone-and-shallow-vs-deep-copying.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-walker.com/blog/php-clone-and-shallow-vs-deep-copying.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PHPOffice/PHPExcel&#34;&gt;PHPExcel&lt;/a&gt; library
recently I saw how Mark Baker overrides the magic &lt;code&gt;__clone&lt;/code&gt; method with
comments about ensuring that cloning will perform a deep copy instead of a
shallow one. This is a topic with which I had not had much experience so I did
some research and experimenting to learn what happens when you use &lt;code&gt;clone&lt;/code&gt; and
the difference between a shallow copy and a deep copy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
